<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: macports | Jimmy Tang]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/categories/macports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-17T15:29:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcftang.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jimmy Tang]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jcftang@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up my work Macbook Air]]></title>
<link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2011/10/21/setting-up-my-work-macbook-air/"/>
<updated>2011-10-21T08:21:00+01:00</updated>
<id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2011/10/21/setting-up-my-work-macbook-air</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everytime when I install, reinstall or setup a mac desktop or laptop I
always tend to install the same set of software that I was using. As time
goes on I change what I like to install and what to use. So I've been
keeping notes and logs of that I usually install first.</p>

<p>For my new job I will mainly be writing documents, writing/modify JAVA
code and other bits and pieces that an integrator/architect or release
engineer might want to do.</p>

<p>I will be trying to automate builds, automate tests, assert that the
software must function as expected and so on.</p>

<p>So down to the list of the things that I have initially installed:</p>

<h2>Binary packages</h2>

<p>Packages that I just grabbed from their respective websites</p>

<ul>
<li>Xcode</li>
<li>JDK - apple developer site</li>
<li>Google Chrome</li>
<li>GitHub Mac</li>
<li>Macports</li>
<li>Eclipse - classic</li>
<li>Perian</li>
<li>iTerm2</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ruby related packages</h2>

<ul>
<li>rvm</li>
<li>showoff</li>
<li>git-scribe</li>
</ul>


<h2>Macports</h2>

<ul>
<li>keychain</li>
<li>git-core</li>
<li>ikiwiki</li>
<li>shiftit</li>
<li>emacs-app</li>
<li>bash-completion</li>
<li>mercurial</li>
<li>mr</li>
<li>ffmpeg</li>
<li>mplayer-devel</li>
<li>dcraw</li>
<li>detox</li>
<li>dos2unix</li>
<li>asciidoc</li>
<li>fossil</li>
<li>zsync</li>
<li>macvim</li>
<li>aria2</li>
<li>openssh</li>
<li>org-mode</li>
<li>tmux</li>
</ul>


<p>The Macports list isn't exactly complete, but it's pretty close to
what I had explicitly installed. Sadly I tried to install gcc45 and
gcc46 because I wanted to play with some codes which needed a fortran
compiler, this failed to install due to some bootstrapping issue of
the fortran compiler during the build.</p>

<p>I've yet to install Haskell and some of the related tools which are
pretty handy for a lazy user. There is also the need for installing
Office for OSX. I wish I could just use plain text.</p>

<p>At somepoint I should grab my previous lists and see what I have
added/removed to my toolbox over the years. So far Lion hasn't been
too bad, but I have yet to develop anything or seriously tried to do
anything too technical on this system so far.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2011/10/21/setting-up-my-work-macbook-air/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>

