<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: java | Jimmy Tang]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/categories/java/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-30T16:06:53+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcftang.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jimmy Tang]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jcftang@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feeling Disconnected From Modern Software Development Tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2011/10/13/feeling-disconnected-from-modern-software-development-tools/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-13T01:09:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2011/10/13/feeling-disconnected-from-modern-software-development-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've recently started a new role as being a senior software engineer
for an Irish National Project and I have had to refresh my OOP skills
with JAVA.</p>

<p>Naturally I gravitated to free and opensource tools to refresh
myself. This lead me to install Eclipse, which is the the EMACS of the
modern world. I've never had much luck with IDE's nor have I liked
using IDE's much in the past since I mainly dealt with codes written
in C, Fortran and if I am lucky Perl or C++. This is because my
background is in Applied Mathematics, Phyiscs and High Performance
Computing and the codes in this general area are just plain old and
written by scientists primarily and not engineers. What this means is
that almost every numerical code out there that I have had the build,
hack at, develop for is setup differently with its own build system,
its own way of laying out the code base, code that depends on specific
compiler bugs. The list of fun things just goes on.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Having to deal with old codes written in "old" languages really makes
the user or system administrator really learn about the build system,
the compliers that are needed, the environment and the dependancy hell
that they get into at times. Because of these experiences, I've yet
again found that JAVA provides lots and lots of support and protection
for the developer. Other nice things that modern languages like JAVA
provide is really the tools that standardise the workflow. This seems
to have had a huge impact on the quality of systems that are produced.</p>

<p>However I really do appreciate the whole TDD concept, but more
importantly the whole concept of Acceptance Testing Driven Development
and Behavioural Driven Development concepts. The features of modern
IDE's hinting users scares me to think that fresh graduates from
university might be too reliant on these modern systems that do too
many things for the developer. It does however give fast feedback to
the developer so that they can learn the language much more easily.</p>

<p>Maybe I just feel like a dinosaur for liking vi/vim or emacs for
writing C programs and shell scripts and liking it. I really do feel
disconnected from what modern developers are doing these
days. Developers these days just have it far easier if JAVA or an
equivalent modern language is used with the appropriate tool. It's
just down to a communication problem of creating the right thing.</p>

<p>By the way this is the first post!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
