<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Jimmy Tang]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-09T09:04:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcftang.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jimmy Tang]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jcftang@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Enterprise Linux Life Cycle Extended to Ten Years]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/02/09/red-hat-enterprise-linux-life-cycle-extended-to-ten-years/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-09T08:16:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/02/09/red-hat-enterprise-linux-life-cycle-extended-to-ten-years</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's all over the internet that RHEL6 and newer releases will have a
life cycle of 10yrs. This is pretty good news for projects that are
deploying systems that have a lifetime of 5yrs or more. Namely Digital
Preservation projects, not having to worry about migration between
point releases of an operating system platform reduces time and costs.</p>

<p>I'm now more likely to target the systems we develop in work towards a
RHEL system (or a RHEL like clone).</p>

<p>Another side effect of this long term support is that it will probably
make life easier for those who have lots of virtual machines running
RHEL. Longer support means less issues with continually migrating
between point releases. From a practical point of view of a
operational sysadmin, this is great. From a developers point of view,
it's also not bad either, software written now (assuming the
requirements haven't changed) will probably work long into the future.</p>

<p>Note: I am not a RHEL (Fedora) fanboy, I used to sysadmin a few
hundred RHEL (scientific linux) based systems. Before that, I used to
sysadmin a few hundred Debian based systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
