<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Jimmy Tang]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcftang.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-30T20:30:47+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcftang.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jimmy Tang]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jcftang@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Slurm User Group Meeting 2012 &rarr;]]></title>
<link href="http://www.bsc.es/marenostrum-support-services/hpc-events-trainings/others/slurm-user-group-meeting-2012"/>
<updated>2012-04-30T20:19:00+01:00</updated>
<id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/slurm-user-group-meeting-2012</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This time the usergroup meeting is in BSC in Spain (this place is
cool, I've been at BSC for a few conferences and meetings before). I
wish I was doing some HPC right now, I'm very tempted to submit an
abstract or two on the last two things with slurm that I was involved
with.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/jcftang/php-slurm">php-slurm</a> package needs
some love, its somewhat in use at work. I just wish I had more time to
fix the memory leaks. There is also
<a href="https://github.com/jcftang/slurm-bank">slurm-bank</a> which is seeing
some good use in work, though it could do with a rewrite in C.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/slurm-user-group-meeting-2012/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[git rerere for long lived feature branches &rarr;]]></title>
<link href="http://progit.org/2010/03/08/rerere.html"/>
<updated>2012-03-11T11:45:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/git-rerere-for-long-lived-feature-branches</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I turned this feature on for a few of my git repos but I had
completely forgotten about it. As far as I recall the feature has been
around for a few years now. It can be turned on globally by doing</p>

<pre><code>git config --global rerere.enabled 1
</code></pre>

<p>It pretty much automates the resolution of conflicts in long lived
branches. I've been lazy recently and I have just doing merges instead
rebasing, which lead me to re-discover <em>git rerere</em>.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/git-rerere-for-long-lived-feature-branches/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Enabling Latent Semantic Indexing for Octopress]]></title>
<link href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/enabling-latent-semantic-indexing-for-octopress/"/>
<updated>2012-03-08T20:02:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/enabling-latent-semantic-indexing-for-octopress</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those that care about having related posts on their <a href="">Octopress</a>
blog. It's actually quite easy to turn it on, it's nice to have and
useful. But it's not enabled by default in Octopress.</p>

<p>This feature already exists in jekyll, enabling this feature in
Octopress is a trival task.</p>

<p>Firstly add this to your <code>_config.yml</code> file</p>

<pre><code>lsi: true
</code></pre>

<p>Then create a file such as <code>source/_includes/custom/asides/related.html</code> with the following
content, add it to one of your asides in <code>_config.yml</code></p>

<p></p>

<pre><code>&lt;section&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul class="posts"&gt;
    {% for post in site.related_posts limit:5 %}
    &lt;li class="related"&gt;
        &lt;a href="{{ root_url }}{{ post.url }}"&gt;{{ post.title }}&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    {% endfor %}
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</code></pre>

<p></p>

<p>It is possible to style the list, but in the above I have chosen to
keep the same style as the recent posts.</p>

<h2>Probable issues with enabling LSI</h2>

<p>There are some issues with enabling LSI in jekyll/octopress, the
primary issue will be performance. The default implementation will be
slow if you have lots of posts to classify. It would be recommended
that rb-gsl be installed to accelerate the classification process.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/enabling-latent-semantic-indexing-for-octopress/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Linux 6.2 is out &rarr;]]></title>
<link href="http://www.scientificlinux.org/distributions/6x/62/"/>
<updated>2012-02-19T18:00:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/02/19/scientific-linux-6-dot-2-is-out</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SL6.2 has been out for a few days now, I haven't had a chance to
really take a look at it, since the more recent SL6 installs I
maintain tend to be tracking the 6x releases. Hopefully SL will try
and keep inline with the upstreams support schedule.</p>

<p>I've a personal preference for deploying SL over CentOS (or any other
recompiles of RHEL). SL tends to be a bit more polished in terms of
not breaking older installs, i.e. the upstream doesn't move point
releases around as CentOS does, SL does not force the end user to run
the latest stable or continually upgrade to the latest point release
to get updates (due to the weird convention CentOS seems to have with
their archives).</p>

<p>It's out, I need to look at it again, especially since ZFS is getting
closer to being ready for a bit more general usage on the server side
and the project that I am working will be needing some machines to be
installed and setup soon.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/02/19/scientific-linux-6-dot-2-is-out/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Rasberry Pi - what I would use it for? &rarr;]]></title>
<link href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"/>
<updated>2012-02-19T14:46:00+00:00</updated>
<id>http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/02/19/rasberry-pi-what-i-would-use-it-for</id>

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the time of writing it seems that the Raspberry Pi site is down,
probably suffering from a slashdot effect. I would imagine almost
every nerd, sheevaplug developer, OLPC developer, DIY'ers who want to
build their own home media centres are looking to get a Raspberry Pi
right now.</p>

<p>So what would I use one of these mini-computers for? I can think up a
range of cool applications for this device, assuming I can order a few
of these to play with. I've got ideas such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>A Tahoe-LAFS storage node, I could attach a few HDD's to one of these
devices and run Tahoe-LAFS on it, these computers are cheap enough
and have a low enough power consumption that I could just have them
on all the time.</li>
<li>A Babeld node, I could have a few of these devices dotted around my
house/apartment to build a mesh network.</li>
<li>A portable computer, not quite a tablet PC with a screen, but it has
enough connectivity to wire it up to a modern monitor or a TV.</li>
<li>A penetration testing device, just wire it up with a few DC
batteries, plug in a wireless card, wrap it up in a water proof
package. Power on, and see how far you can throw it at your target,
I can see endless possibilities for this device for pen-testing.</li>
</ul>


<p>I wonder if the device will ever be able to be powered via the USB
port or the the ethernet port. I can see some interesting uses for
this device in data centres for monitoring the network, power
consumption and a host of other things.</p>

<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://jcftang.github.com/blog/2012/02/19/rasberry-pi-what-i-would-use-it-for/">&infin; Permalink</a></p>

]]></content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>

